Register to The Seymour Shifrin Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Seymour Shifrin Papers
1940-1982
MSS 36
Yale University Music Library
26
(35 boxes)
Music, correspondence and other papers, photographs, and additional materials by and about the American composer and educator Seymour Shifrin (1926-1979)
Shifrin, Seymour, 1926-1979
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Seymour Shifrin Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Miriam L. Shifrin in 1982.
Arrangement
In 9 series as follows: I. Music. II. Correspondence. III. Programs. IV. Clippings. V. Writings. VI. Biographical material. VII. Manuscripts given to Shifrin by Roger Sessions. VIII. Miscellaneous items. IX. Musical instruments.
Scope and Contents
The Seymour Shifrin Papers contain sketches, manuscript scores, and published editions of Shifrin's musical compositions, including orchestral works, chamber music, keyboard pieces, choral music, and songs. The Papers also hold autograph manuscripts of Roger Sessions' sonatas for unaccompanied violin and for piano. Seymour and Miriam Shifrin's correspondence includes letters to and from performers, composers, publishers, musical organizations, and family members. Shifrin's life and work are further documented by: programs; newspaper and magazine clippings; papers, addresses, and essays written by Shifrin; photographs; and musical instruments.
Biographical / Historical
Seymour Jack Shifrin was born in Brooklyn, New York on February 28, 1926. After graduating from the New York High School of Music and Art, he studied privately with the composer William Schuman, and then attended Columbia University, where he received the BA and the MA in 1947 and 1949, respectively. His principal composition teacher at Columbia was Otto Luening. Shifrin taught at Columbia in 1949-1950 and at the City College of New York in 1950-51. The next year, he studied in Paris with Darius Milhaud. In 1952 he was appointed to the faculty of the University of California at Berkeley, where he remained until 1966, when he became a professor at Brandeis University.
Shifrin's works have been performed by many prominent ensembles and soloists, including the Boston Symphony Orchestra, the Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra, the Juilliard, Fine Arts, and Galimir Quartets, and Alfred Brendel, Stephen Bishop, Bethany Beardslee, and Jan de Gaetani. He received numerous honors, including the Boston Symphony's Horblit Award, as well as grants from the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Institute of Arts and Letters, and the Koussevitzky, Guggenheim, and Fulbright foundations.
Seymour Shifrin died in Boston on September 26, 1979, at the age of 53.
Composers -- Correspondence; Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Piano music; Songs; String quartets -- Scores; Arrigo, Girolamo; Babbitt, Milton, 1916-2011; Barkin, Elaine, 1932-; Beardslee, Bethany; Berger, Arthur, 1912-2003; Boone, Charles, 1939-; Boretz, Benjamin, 1934-; Boyden, David D. (David Dodge), 1910-1986; Boykan, Martin, 1931-; Brendel, Alfred, 1931-; Brody, Martin, 1949-; Cone, Edward T., 1917-2004; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990; Curtis, Alan, 1934-2015; Dahl, Ingolf, 1912-1970; Dallapiccola, Luigi, 1904-1975; De Gaetani, Jan, 1933-1989; Einem, Gottfried von, 1918-1996; Felciano, Richard, 1930-; Finney, Ross Lee, 1906-1997; Forte, Allen, 1926-2014; Frankenstein, Alfred V. (Alfred Victor), 1906-1981; Gaburo, Kenneth, 1926-1993; Harbison, John, 1938-; Harris, Donald; Helps, Robert, 1928-2001; Hoffman, Richard, 1831-1909; Imbrie, Andrew, 1921-2007; Kirchner, Leon, 1919-2009; Kohn, Karl, 1926-; Kolisch, Rudolf, 1896-1978; LeFanu, Nicola, 1947-; Lewin, David, 1933-2003; Luening, Otto, 1900-1996; Martirano, Salvatore, 1927-1995; Meyer, Leonard B.; Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974; Miller, Robert, 1930-1981; Mitchell, William J. (William John), 1906-1971; Moore, Douglas, 1893-1969; Newcomb, Anthony, 1943-; Nin-Culmell, Joaquín, 1908-2004; Oppens, Ursula, 1944-; Perle, George, 1915-2009; Pollikoff, Max, 1904-1984; Rifkin, Joshua; Schuman, William, 1910-1992; Sessions, Roger, 1896-1985; Shapero, Harold, 1920-2013; Shapey, Ralph, 1921-2002; Shifrin, Miriam; Shifrin, Seymour, 1926-1979; Sims, Ezra, 1928-2015; Spies, Claudio, 1925-; Stein, Leonard, 1916-2004; Steinberg, Michael, 1928-2009; Stockhausen, Karlheinz, 1928-2007; Swift, Richard, 1927-2003; Thomas, John, 1927-2001; Treitler, Leo, 1931-; Wernick, Richard, 1934-; Winkler, Peter, 1943-; Wyner, Yehudi, 1929-
- Music, 1943-1979; Series I; 9.4' (6 boxes)
  General
  The music series of the Shifrin papers includes holograph, manuscript, and published music by Shifrin. This series is divided into six subseries (A-F) by genre. An index gives access by title. Cross references have been made from parts of works to the title under which they are being described. Transcription of the title page is given only when it contains information not stated in the uniform title. The first entry under a uniform title contains the fullest description. The date is noted only in the first entry unless it varies. Subseries A-E are arranged alphabetically by title. The subseries A (Student Works) contains works written from 1943-1946 while Shifrin was a student.
  Items are arranged in boxes chronologically by date of composition. The folders are numbered consecutively throughout the entire series. There is one known work by Shifrin not contained in this collection, which is "Waltz" dating from 1977.
  - Student Works, 1943-1946; I.A
    - [American gothic] American gothic: a work for symphonic band, 1946 Aug. 22.; 1 condensed score (6 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Holograph in ink (transparency).
    - [Canonic exercises] Canonic exercises, 1946 Jun. 23-Sep. 30.; [6] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Holograph in ink.
      Contains eight exercises for keyboard with pencil sketches and jottings.
    - [Cantata (1943)] Cantata for chorus and orchestra / [poet unknown], 1943 Mar. 14.; 1 score ([19] p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Holograph signed, in ink, with red rehearsal marks.
    - [Duets, clarinet, bassoon] Duo for clarinet and bassoon, 1946 Aug. 28.; 1 score (7 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Bound photocopy laid in.
    - [Duets, viola, violoncello] Duo for viola and violoncello, 1946 Jun.; 1 score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Holograph signed, in ink.
    - Duo for clarinet and bassoon
      See: Duets, clarinet, bassoon.
    - Duo for viola and violoncello
      See: Duets, viola, violoncello.
    - [Fugue trio] A Fugue trio, 1946 Aug.; 1 score (8 p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      For violin, viola, and violoncello.
    - [Furioso] Furioso, 1946 Jun.; [2] p. of music. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      For piano.
      Pencil sketch on back.
  - Songs (and other vocal), I.B
    - [Birthday greeting] A Birthday greeting / text: William Shakespeare., [1976].; 1 score (2 sheets); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 49)
      Holograph, signed (photocopy).
      For soprano and piano.
      On first sheet: For Milton - on your 60th birthday, with regard and affection - mindful of how your work has enriched and enlarged our profession. In friendship.
      Reprint. Originally published in: Perspectives of new music (1976), p. 200-201.
    - [Birthday greeting (Sketches)], 1 score ([3] p.); 27 cm. (Box 6, Folder 49)
      Holograph in pencil.
      One sheet has been cut.
    - [Cat and the moon] The Cat and the moon / [words by] W.B. Yeats, 1949 Jun. 18.; 1 score ([8] p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      On title page: For M.S.
      Holograph transparency and photocopy of score laid in.
    - Der Bach hat leise melodien...
      See: Early poems.
    - [Early poems] Two early poems / by Rainer Maria Rilke, 1947 Oct. 20.; 1 score (6 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      For high voice and piano.
      Date appears at end of first song.
      Pencil sketch on bottom of p. [2].
      Bound photocopy of score and additional photocopy of first song laid in.
    - Five songs for soprano and piano
      See: Songs (1979).
    - [Mir war so weh] Mir war so weh / [Rainer Maria Rilke], 1948 Oct.; 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Title from first line of text.
    - [No second Troy] No second Troy / [words by] William Butler Yeats, 1951 Feb. 26.; 1 score (4 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Photocopy laid in.
    - [No second Troy (Sketches)], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Holograph in pencil with red pencil marks.
    - [Renaissance garland] A Renaissance garland, 1975 Oct. 11.; 1 score (31 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 6, Folder 48)
      For soprano, tenor, recorders (SATB), lute, viols (TB), and percussion.
      On title page: For Mir.
      At end: Natick.
      Includes additional five sheets of score rewritten with recorder parts untransposed.
      Contents: Sonnet (text, Sir Thomas Wyatt) -- Ballad (text, anonymous) -- An excellent sonnet of a nimph (text, Sir Philip Sidney) -- Sonnet (text, William Shakespeare).
    - [Renaissance garland (Sketches)], 1 score ([35] p.); 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 48)
      Holograph in pencil and ink.
      Includes performance instructions ([6] sheets) and texts printed separately ([6] sheets).
    - [Rest sweet nimphs] Rest sweet nimphs / [anonymous], 1966 spring.; 1 score (2 sheets); 20-35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 36)
      For soprano and clarinet.
      On top of first page: For the three newborn babes dear to me: Eva Swackhamer, Martha Senturia, Lea Spies.
      Photocopy and additional set of transparencies laid in.
    - [Rest sweet nimphs (Sketches)], 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Ripeness is all
      See: Birthday greeting.
    - [Satires of circumstance] Satires of circumstance / to poems by Thomas Hardy, 1964 Aug. 26.; 1 score (50 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 4, Folder 34)
      For soprano, piccolo/flute, clarinet, violin, violoncello, double bass, and piano.
      On title page: Commissioned by the Fromm Music Foundation for Paul Fromm.
      At end: Berkeley.
      Bound photocopy of score and typescript of text laid in.
    - [Satires of circumstance (Sketches)], [6] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 34)
      Contains [12] p. of errata in pencil and ink.
    - [Songs (1979)] Five songs for soprano and piano, 1979 May 13.; 1 score (25 sheets); 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 52)
      At end: Natick, MA.
      Sheets have been out.
      Bound photocopy with orchestrational outline of piano part in pencil laid in.
      Contents: Sonnett (text, William Shakespeare) -- White Flowers (text, Michael Fried) -- The Pool (text, Michael Fried) -- Anacreontike (text, Robert Herrick) -- Astrophil and Stella, Sonnet 39 (text, Sir Philip Sidney).
    - [Songs (1979) (Sketches)], 1 score ([24] p.); 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - [Songs (1979); arr.] [Five songs for soprano and piano], 1 score (37 sheets); 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 51)
      Holograph in pencil (transparency).
      Acc. arr. for orchestra.
      Annotations in red by Martin Boykan.
      Incomplete. Final movement unfinished.
    - [Spring and fall] Spring and fall: to a young child / [by] Gerard Manley Hopkins, 1952 Dec.; 1 score (4 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      For medium voice and piano.
    - [Spring and fall (Sketches)], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Two early poems
    - Weist du
  - Orchestral and Chamber Music, I.C
    - American gothic
      See: A. Student Works. American gothic.
    - [Chamber symphony] Chamber symphony, 1954 Jan.; 1 score (129 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Holograph signed, in ink (transparency).
      For flute, clarinet I-II, bass clarinet, horn I-II, trombone (TB), and strings.
    - [Chamber symphony (Sketches)], 1 score ([48, 49, 9, 31, 49] p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Complete pencil sketch of first movement and incomplete copy in ink.
      Complete pencil sketch of second movement with red pencil marks and incomplete copy in ink.
      Complete pencil sketch of third movement with blue and red pencil marks.
      Dates at end of each movement: 1. (1952 May) -- II. (1953 Jul. 27) -- III. (1953 Dec. 25).
    - [Concert piece] Concert piece for solo violin, 1959 Dec. 16.; 1 score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 30)
      On title page: For Austin Reller.
      Photocopy with red marks laid in.
    - [Concert piece (Sketches)] Concert piece for solo violin, 1959 Dec.; [10] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - [Duets, violin, piano] Duo for violin and piano, 1969 Jan. 2.; 1 score (16 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 5, Folder 42)
      On title page: For Rose Mary Harbison.
      Bound Photocopy laid in.
    - [Duets, violin, piano (Sketches)] Duo [for violin and piano], 1968-1969.; 1 score ([17] p.); 34 cm. (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Duo for clarinet and bassoon
      See: A. Student Works. Duets, clarinet, bassoon.
    - Duo for viola and violoncello
      See: A. Student Works. Duets, viola, violoncello.
    - Duo for violin and piano
      See: Duets, violin, piano.
    - A Fugue trio
      See: A. Student Works. Fugue trio.
    - [In eius memoriam] In eius memoriam, 1968 Feb. 6.; 1 score (14 sheets) + 3 parts; 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 41)
      For flute, clarinet, violin, violoncello, and piano.
      Parts incomplete, lacking piano. Both string parts on same sheet.
      Photocopy with pencil marks laid in.
    - [In eius memoriam] In Eius Memoriam / Seymour Shifrin. -- New York: C.F. Peters, c1976., 1 miniature score (17 p.); 30 cm. (Box 5, Folder 41)
      Duration: 6:00.
      Pub. no.: Edition Peters 66479a.
    - [In eius memoriam (Sketches)], 1 score ([10] p.); 34 cm. (Box 5, Folder 41)
      Includes three typescript copies (carbon) of a letter by Seymour Shifrin concerning phrasing.
    - [Music for orchestra] Music for orchestra, 1948 Jul. 10.; 1 score (22 sheets); 43 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Two bound photocopies laid in.
    - [Music for the young] Music for the young, c1968.; 1 score ([5] p.); 33-37 cm. (Box 4, Folder 40)
      Photocopy of manuscript
      Inscription in second movement: Commissioned by the University of Illinois String Research Project under a grant by the U.S. Office of Education.
      Two additional photocopies of score, one with corrections by the editor in red and blue ink, laid in.
      Contents: Play for the young (violin) -- Duettino (violin, piano) -- Lullaby (violin, violoncello).
    - [Nick of time] The Nick of time, 1978 Feb. 27.; 1 score (52 sheets) + 6 parts; 34-38 cm. (Box 6, Folder 50)
      For flute, clarinet, violin, violoncello, contrabass, piano, and percussion.
      On title page: Dedicated to Speculum Musicae. With the aid of a grant from the National Endowment for the Arts.
      Parts incomplete, lacks piano.
      For special required instrument see: IX. MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS. Drums.
    - [Pieces, orchestra] Three pieces for orchestra, 1958 Dec. 21.; 1 score (93 sheets); 43 cm. (Box 3, Folder 27)
      On title page: Commissioned for the League of Composers - I.S.C.M. by Richard Rogers and Oscar Hammerstein.
      Bound photocopy of score with pencil marks laid in.
    - [Quartets, strings (1949)] String quartet, 1949 Mar.; 1 score (33 sheets) + 4 parts; 34-38 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Holograph and manuscript in ink (transparency).
      Includes second set of manuscript parts in unknown hand.
      Two photocopies of score laid in.
    - [Quartets, strings (1949)], 1 score ([11], [17] p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      First 90 bars in pencil and ink ([ll] p.).
      Pencil sketch ([17] p.) bars 90-295.
    - [Quartets, strings (1949)] Streichquartett = String Quartet / Seymour Shifrin. -- Berlin: Bote and Book, c1961., 1 miniature score (35 p.); 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Duration: 17:00.
      Pl. no.: B & B 21 681.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1] String quartet no. 1, 1947 Aug. 15-Nov. 19.; 1 score (15, 21, 15 p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Holograph in ink, with pencil additions.
      Two copies of first movement.
      Dates at end of each movement: 1. (1947 Aug. 15) -- II. (1947 Oct. 15) -- III. (1947 Nov. 19).
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1] String quartet no. 1, 1947 Nov. 19.; 1 score (39 sheets) + 4 parts; 34-38 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2] String quartet no. 2, 1962 Mar. 25.; 1 score (30 sheets) + 4 parts; 35-38 cm. (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Photocopy of score laid in.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 3] String quartet no. 3, 1966 May 31.; 1 score (26 sheets); 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 35)
      Holograph signed, in pencil (carbon on transparency).
      On title page: For the Serge Koussevitzky Music Foundation in the Library of Congress, dedicated to the memory of Serge and Natalie Koussevitzky.
      Contains [9] p. of errata.
      Bound photocopy with red marks laid in.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 3 (Sketches)], 1 score ([19] p.); 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 4] String quartet no. 4, 1967 Jan. 29.; 1 score (38 sheets) + 4 parts; 36 cm. (Box 4, Folder 38-39)
      On title page: Commissioned by the Fine Arts Music Foundation of Chicago for the members of the Fine Arts String Quartet: Leonard Sorkin, Abram Loft, Gerald Stanick (Bernard Zaslav), George Sopkin.
      At end: Natick, Mass.
      Includes two photocopies of the second movement.
      Parts are for second movement only (includes two copies each of viola and violoncello parts).
      Two bound photocopies of score, one with annotations by Seymour Shifrin in red and pencil, laid in.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 4 (Sketches)], 1 score ([42] p.); 31-34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 37)
      Includes [5] p. of errata in pencil and [3] typescript sheets with additional marks in ink.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 5] String quartet no. 5, 1972 Aug. 14.; 1 score (29 p.); 38 cm. (Box 5, Folder 45)
      Holograph in ink, bound, with marks in red and pencil (photocopy).
      On title page: Commissioned by the University of Michigan for the Stanley Quartet: Gilbert Ross, Gustave Rosseels, Robert Courte, Jerome Jelinek.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 5 (Sketches)], 1 score ([32] p.); 34 cm. (Box 5, Folder 45)
      Holograph in pencil with marks in red and ink.
    - A Renaissance garland
      See: B. Songs. Renaissance garland.
    - Rest sweet nimphs
      See: B. Songs. Rest sweet nimphs.
    - Satires of circumstance
      See: B. Songs. Satires of circumstance.
    - Serenade for five instruments
      See: Serenade, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, viola.
    - [Serenade, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, viola] Serenade for five instruments, [1954].; 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Manuscript in ink.
      Two incomplete sets. First lacks piano part, second set is for third movement only (also lacks piano).
    - [Sonata, violoncello, piano] Sonata no. 1 for violoncello and piano, 1948 Mar. 28.; 1 score (14, 6, 12 p.) + 2 parts; 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Holograph in ink, with pencil additions (transparency).
      Includes two copies of first movement.
    - [Sonata, violoncello, piano], 1 score (30 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Some sheets have been cut.
    - Three pieces for orchestra
      See: Pieces, orchestra.
    - [Trios, piano, strings] Trio for violin, violoncello, and piano, 1974 Nov. 30.; 1 score (19 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - [Trios, piano, strings (Sketches)], 1 score ([14] p.); 34 cm. (Box 5, Folder 47)
      Includes letter and one typescript sheet of errata.
    - [Trios, strings] String trio, [no date].; 1 score ([3] p.) + 3 parts; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Keyboard Works, I.D
    - [Air for Teddy] Air for Teddy, [no date].; [1] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 53)
      With: The Organ grinder.
    - Canonic exercises
      See: A. Student Works. Canonic exercises.
    - [Cantos] Four cantos for piano, 1948 Sep. 1.; [4] sheets of music; 38 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - [Cantos (Sketches)], [9] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Holograph in ink and pencil.
      Two sketches of first movement, one in ink, one pencil.
    - [Composition, piano] Composition for piano, 1950 Dec. 8; [18] sheets of music; 38 cm. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Some sheets have been out.
      Additional set of ms. transparencies and photocopy of score laid in.
      Photographic reduction of score, two sets, laid in (28 x 35 cm.). First set incomplete (pp. 1-12 only). Second set has pencil and red ink marks. Two pages of score per sheet.
    - [Composition, piano (Sketches)] Composition for piano, 1950 Dec.; [30] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Holograph in ink (12 p.) and pencil.
    - Four cantos for piano
      See: Cantos.
    - Furioso
      See: A. Student Works. Furioso.
    - [Lullaby for Elly] Lullaby for Elly, [no date].; [2] sheets of music; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 54)
      Photocopy of manuscript.
      For two voices or instruments.
    - [Modern temper] The Modern temper: a dance for piano four-hands., 1959 Aug. 22.; 11 sheets of music; 38 cm. (Box 3, Folder 28)
      On title page: Commissioned for the Composers Forum, San Francisco, by Peggy and Milton Salkind.
    - [Organ grinder] The Organ grinder, [no date].; [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 53)
      On title page: For Heidi Goldberg. Hommage a Stravinsky.
      With: Air for Teddy.
    - [Responses] Responses for piano solo, 1973 Jul. 30.; 10 sheets of music; 34 cm. (Box 5, Folder 46)
      On title page: For Robert Helps.
      At end: Natick, Berkeley.
      Three photocopies with marks in ink laid in. One lacks title page.
    - [Responses (Sketches)], [5] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - [Trauermusik] Trauermusik, 1956 Dec.; 5 sheets of music; 34 cm. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Choral Works, I.E
    - Cantata (1943)
      See: A. Student Works. Cantata (1943).
    - [Cantata to Sophoclean choruses], 1 score (116 [i.e. 115] p.), bound; 38 cm. (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Holograph signed (photocopy).
      For women's voices (SSAA), string quartet, and piano (first movement); for chorus (SATB) and orchestra (2nd-4th movement).
      Words from Oedipus Rex and Antigone by Sophocles. Translation by W.B. Yeats and Dudley Fitts. Dates at end of each movement: Lament for Oedipus (1955 Oct. 31) -- Ode (Zurich, 1956 Nov. 8) -- Paean (Brioni, Switzerland, 1957 Jun. 28) -- Ode (Berkeley, 1957 Dec. 30). Additional photocopy with red pencil marks laid in. Also contains four typescript sets of texts for first movement.
    - [Cantata to Sophoclean choruses], 1 score (116 p.); 34-38 cm. (Box 3, Folder 26.5)
      Holograph, in ink (transparency).
      On container: Copyright 1976 by C.F. Peters Corporation.
    - [Cantata to Sophoclean choruses (Sketches)], 1 score ([8] p., [16] sheets); 22-34 cm. (Box 3, Folder 23)
      String quartet acc. arr. for string orchestra.
      Contents: Lament for Oedipus.
    - [Cantata to Sophoclean choruses (Sketches)], 1 score ([21] p.); 34 cm. (Box 3, Folder 23)
      Holograph in pencil with blue and red pencil marks.
    - [Cantata to Sophoclean choruses (Sketches)], 1 score ([250] p.); 27 cm. (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Contents: Ode -- Paean -- Ode.
    - [Cantata to Sophoclean choruses (Sketches)], 1 score ([23], [13], [4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - [Chronicles] Chronicles: Cantata to texts from the Old Testament, 1970 Aug. 2.; 1 score (73 p.); 44 cm. (Box 5, Folder 44)
      Holograph in ink, bound (photocopy).
      For soloists (TBar.B), chorus, and orchestra.
      Romanized Hebrew text with partial English translation added in red ink by Seymour Shifrin.
      On title page: Commissioned by the Congregation Emanu-El, San Francisco, on the occasion of their 120th anniversary. Dedicated to my parents on their 50th anniversary. At end: Natick.